<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on Yapeng Zhang - PhD student in Astronomy</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on Yapeng Zhang - PhD student in Astronomy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 17:12:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transmission spectroscopy of ultra-hot Jupiters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/project/uhj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 20:33:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/project/uhj/</guid>
      <description>Ultra hot Jupiter (UHJ) is an extreme class of exoplanets which gets really close to its host star, typically within 0.05 au, and with an eqlibrium temperature higher than 2000K. Becasue of the extreme conditions, they are excellent laboratories for the atmospheric characterization. At such high temperature, many species are mainly in the atomic form, such as atomic H, Na, Fe, and inoic Fe+. High temperature contrast is typically found between the day and night side of these planets, which can lead to day-to-night-side winds and chemical asymmetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:48:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/cv/</guid>
      <description>Education 2019-2023 PhD, Astrophysics, Leiden University, NL Thesis: Characterization of exoplanet atmospheres with medium-/high-resolution spectroscopy Advisor: Ignas Snellen 2017-2019 MSc, Astronomy and Data Science, cum laude, Leiden University, NL Thesis: Effects of dust evolution and gap formation on multi-wavelength continuum observations of TW Hydrae disk Advisor: Michiel Hogerheijde 2013-2017 BSc, Astronomy, Nanjing University, China Thesis: Planet formation in highly inclined binary systems Advisor: Jiwei Xie 2016.06-08 Summer intern, European Southern Observatory Thesis: Dipper stars in the Upper Sco and ρ Oph star forming regions identified from the K2 mission Advisor: Valentin Ivanov Talks Invited seminar talk 2021-2022 Exoplanet seminar at University of Cambridge, ETH Zurich Exocoffee journal club at MPIA/APEx Heidelberg Contributed talk 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:47:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/publication/</guid>
      <description>First-author Zhang, Y., Snellen, I. A. G., Wyttenbach, A., Nielsen, L. D., Lendl, M., Casasayas-Barris, N., Chaverot, G., Kesseli, A. Y., Lovis, C., Pepe, F. A., Psaridi, A., Seidel, J. V., Udry, S., &amp;amp; Ulmer-Moll, S. (2022) Transmission spectroscopy of the ultra-hot Jupiter MASCARA-4b. Disentangling the hydrostatic and exospheric regimes of ultra-hot Jupiters. Astronomy and Astrophysics, in press
Zhang, Y., Snellen, I. A. G., &amp;amp; Mollière, P. (2021) The 12CO/13CO isotopologue ratio of a young, isolated brown dwarf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isotope ratios in exopanet atmospheres</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/project/isotope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 14:47:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/project/isotope/</guid>
      <description>Isotope abundance ratios play an important role in astronomy and planetary sciences, providing insights in the origin and evolution of the Solar System, interstellar chemistry, and stellar nucleosynthesis. Isotopologue abundance ratios in exoplanet atmospheres have been proposed to be new observational probes for planet formation (Molliere &amp;amp; Snellen 2019; Morley et al. 2019) as inspired by solar system measurements. In the Solar System, deuterium-to-hydrogen (D/H) ratios demonstrate significant variations across planets, comets, and meteorites, providing important insights into the origin and evolution of the system (see Figure 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium airglow emission from close-in hot Jupiters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/project/helium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:47:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/project/helium/</guid>
      <description> Illustration of He I emission from an exosphere of a close-in planet.It has recently been detected in the transmission spectra of a handful of planets. The isotropic reemission will lead to helium airglow that may be observable at other orbital phases. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet formation in highly inclined binary systems</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/project/inclined/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 20:56:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/project/inclined/</guid>
      <description>Animation of a typical simulation with a binary separation of 80 au and inclination of 60 deg. The orbits of planetary embryos (denoted with the cyan spheres) were initially aligned with respect to the spin of the primary but finally aligned with respect to the binary orbit (not shown). The green arrows denote the normal lines of the primary spin plane (L_spin) and of the binary orbital plane (L_binary) respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
