<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Yapeng Zhang - PhD student in Astronomy</title><link>https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Yapeng Zhang - PhD student in Astronomy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 20:33:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CV</title><link>https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/cv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:48:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/cv/</guid><description>Education &amp;amp; Experience 2019-2023 PhD, Astrophysics, Leiden University, NL Thesis: Characterization of exoplanet atmospheres with medium-/high-resolution spectroscopy Advisor: Ignas Snellen 2017-2019 MSc, Astronomy and Data Science, cum laude, Leiden University, NL Thesis: Effects of dust evolution and gap formation on multi-wavelength continuum observations of TW Hydrae disk Advisor: Michiel Hogerheijde 2013-2017 BSc, Astronomy, Nanjing University, China Thesis: Planet formation in highly inclined binary systems Advisor: Jiwei Xie 2016.06-08 Summer intern, European Southern Observatory Thesis: Dipper stars in the Upper Sco and ρ Oph star forming regions identified from the K2 mission Advisor: Valentin Ivanov Talks Invited seminar talk 2021-2022 Exoplanet seminar at University of Cambridge, ETH Zurich Exocoffee journal club at MPIA/APEx Heidelberg Contributed talk 2022.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/publication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:47:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://yapenzhang.github.io/post/publication/</guid><description>First-author Zhang, Y., Snellen, I. A. G., Wyttenbach, A., Nielsen, L. D., Lendl, M., Casasayas-Barris, N., Chaverot, G., Kesseli, A. Y., Lovis, C., Pepe, F. A., Psaridi, A., Seidel, J. V., Udry, S., &amp;amp; Ulmer-Moll, S. (2022) Transmission spectroscopy of the ultra-hot Jupiter MASCARA-4b. Disentangling the hydrostatic and exospheric regimes of ultra-hot Jupiters. Astronomy and Astrophysics, in press
Zhang, Y., Snellen, I. A. G., &amp;amp; Mollière, P. (2021) The 12CO/13CO isotopologue ratio of a young, isolated brown dwarf.</description></item></channel></rss>